<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Custom Analysis on Masood Sadat Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/custom-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Custom Analysis on Masood Sadat Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/custom-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspecting Konkor 1397 (2018) Data</title>
      <link>/post/inspecting-konkor-1397-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/inspecting-konkor-1397-data/</guid>
      <description>Read about the Konkor exam in Afghanistan in the footnote.1
 Disclaimer: Konkor data is not public, but Konkor results dataset was publicly shared by various individuals on social media on August 1, 2018. As the dataset include personal information, I will aggregate the results at provincial level without using personal information such as names.
The data has the following variables or indicators:
  Variables Description    name Name of test taker  gender Gender of test taker  gradyear Year graduated from high school  score Konkor test score  province Name of Province  cheat Whether test taker was caught cheating  fail Whether test taker failed or admitted to university  pvt_univ Whether test taker graduated from a private university  univ_prov Not admitted but eligible for Private Universities    Participation Overall, approximately 159 thousand high school graduates took part in the konkor exam of 1397, from all provinces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions About Electricity in Afghanistan: Insights From the Survey of the Afghan People</title>
      <link>/posts/perceptions-about-electricity-in-afghanistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/perceptions-about-electricity-in-afghanistan/</guid>
      <description>About This analysis uses the Survey of the Afghan People data, an annual survey of perceptions from a nationally representative sample of Afghans. The survey has collected attitudes and perceptions uninterruptedly since 2006, with over 97,000 Afghans taking part. The the latest survey report here, or download the raw data here.  Awareness of Government Supplied Electricity Projects  Key Questions: x11as. I am going to read a list of projects that may or may not have been implemented in your area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>