<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Masood Sadat Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Masood Sadat Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Konkor 1397 (2018) Results</title>
      <link>/post/analyzing-konkor-1397-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analyzing-konkor-1397-results/</guid>
      <description>Read about the Konkor exam in Afghanistan in the footnote.1
 Konkor data is not public, but Konkor results dataset was publicly shared by various individuals on social media on August 1, 2018. As the dataset include personal information, I will aggregate the results at provincial level without using personal information such as names.
 The nationwide university entrance exam for public universities is called Konkor exam. Every year, tens of thousands of students from all over the country participate in this exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Data Manipulation with dplyr</title>
      <link>/post/week-3-data-manipulation-with-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/week-3-data-manipulation-with-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>About tidyverse Pipe Operator About dplyr Select Slice Filter Mutate    About tidyverse There are thousands of packages developed by equally large number of developers that provide new features or improve R’s features. One of the most influential and useful set of packages is tidyverse which is a collection of other packages for data manipulation, exploration and visualization. All tidyverse packages share an underlying design philosophy, grammar, and data structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: On Data Frames and Intro to ggplot2 For Making Graphs</title>
      <link>/post/week-2-on-data-frames-and-intro-to-ggplot2-for-making-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/week-2-on-data-frames-and-intro-to-ggplot2-for-making-graphs/</guid>
      <description>Data Frames Data Frame Index Create New Column/Variable Inspect Data Frames  Basic Graphs with ggplot2 Components of ggplot2 Graphs Types of Plots With ggplot2 Apply a Different Theme    Data Frames Data frames are the most widely used data object in R. A data frame is a collection of vectors of the same length, which is also called columns. Each column have their own data type (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/posts/week-1-introduction-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/week-1-introduction-to-r/</guid>
      <description>R and RStudio RStudio interface Basics Arithmetic Assignment Data types in R Data objects in R  Vectors Vectors Arithmetic Vector index  Matrices Matrix index Matrix Arithmetic Joining matrices  Data frames Creating data frame Data frame index Column and Row Names  Lists Relational Operators   R and RStudio R is an opern-source programming language for statistical analysis. Being open-source, unlike similar software such as Stata, SAS and SPSS, it is free to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Tweets with R</title>
      <link>/posts/collecting-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/collecting-tweets/</guid>
      <description>In this post I am going to download tweets using twitteR package.
To being, you have to have a twitter account. If you do not have, create a twitter account on twitter.com.
 Create a twitter application on apps.twitter.com. There, you have to insert a number of information, see the following screen shot.
   Once, you created an application, you will have access to API Key and API Secret in the Keys and Access Tokens tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a local folder to GitHub using the command line</title>
      <link>/posts/add-a-local-folder-to-github-using-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/add-a-local-folder-to-github-using-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Did you know you can upload almost anything on Github.com?
Recently, I have started uploading many of my files on github, besides code. I do it because I am working on two different computers, one at work and one at home, and I think this is a great way to keep my work synchronized. I am not going to talk more about using github at this point–maybe I will have a dedicated post on that later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear regression with R</title>
      <link>/posts/linear-regression-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linear-regression-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Estimating linear regression Before starting, I am going to load a number of utility libraries for this session.
library(tidyverse) library(broom) library(plotly) A simple linear regression using mtcars dataset. I want to look at how weight of a car is associated with how many miles a car travels per gallon of gasoline–an indicator of fuel economy. I am going to look at their summary and scatter plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection of Provinces for Monitoring in SAP 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/selection-of-provinces-for-monitoring-in-sap-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/selection-of-provinces-for-monitoring-in-sap-2018/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Asia Foundation (TAF) employs a number of methods to ensure data quality for the Survey of the Afghan People (SAP). The most important quality controls are (1) third party monitoringy, and (2) logic tests. The third party monitoring is carried out on 10% of all surveys by an independent company, and 25% are subject to monitoring from the data collection company. The third party monitoring started in 2014, and since then Sayara Research has been the implementing partner for this activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Website with R, blogdown, Hugo, and netlify.com</title>
      <link>/posts/build-a-website-with-r-blogdown-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/build-a-website-with-r-blogdown-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>One of the coolest things I have learned in R recently is creating a website with blogdown package. The blogdown websites are created and maintained from within R mostly, which is the best part about it if you are a R user. There are many sources that provide details and reasons for using blogdown, so I will not dwell on that. Instead, I am going to provide a brief and to-the-point tutorial on how to start your website with R and blogdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tutorial for Analysing Survey of the Afghan People in R</title>
      <link>/posts/a-tutorial-for-analysing-survey-of-the-afghan-people-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-tutorial-for-analysing-survey-of-the-afghan-people-in-r/</guid>
      <description>1 About the Survey of the Afghan People Since 2006, The Asia Foundation conducts the Survey of the Afghan People, a nationally-representative annual survey. The Survey reflects perceptions about a broad range of topics including security, development, governance, service delivery, women’s rights, and migration. The Survey is broadly used by policy makers, academics, non-governmental organizations working in and on Afghanistan. The Foundation make the Survey’s data public on its website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plot Missing Values</title>
      <link>/posts/plot-missing-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/plot-missing-values/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will explore visdat package to visualize missing values. Then, we will recreate a similar plot using ggplot2 package. Next, using the ggplot2 method, we will visualize other numeric or character values in a dataset. Finally, using the ggplot2 method, we will create a custom function that will plot any value in any dataset.
 There are many ways to inspect and find about missing values in a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of GitHub Through Command Line</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-05-18-basics_of_github_through_command_line/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-05-18-basics_of_github_through_command_line/</guid>
      <description>Create account and repository on github.com Go to github.com and create an account. Once, account is created, create a repository in Repositories tab and click on the green button New. The following page opens.
 NOTE: A repository is something like a project folder.
   Copy repository URL After a new repository is created, copy the clone url link. This link is used to clone the repository from server to the computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions About Electricity in Afghanistan: Insights From the Survey of the Afghan People</title>
      <link>/posts/perceptions-about-electricity-in-afghanistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/perceptions-about-electricity-in-afghanistan/</guid>
      <description>About This analysis is prepared following a requrest from Peter Stevenson of Mercy Corps–Afghanistan.
This analysis uses the Survey of the Afghan People data, an annual survey of perceptions from a nationally representative sample of Afghans. The survey has collected attitudes and perceptions uninterruptedly since 2006, with over 97,000 Afghans taking part. The the latest survey report here, or download the raw data here.  Awareness of Government Supplied Electricity Projects  Key Questions: x11as.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>